leupold.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy | Leupold

Last Update: 6/4/2018, 2018

Leupold® & Stevens, Inc. (“ **Leupold** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **our** ,” or “ **us** ”) respects your privacy, and we are committed to protecting it in accordance with this policy. This privacy policy identifies the type of information we collect from visitors of our website [www.leupold.com](http://www.leupold.com/) (the “ **Website** ”) and how we use this information. Your use of this Website may also be governed by other separate terms, conditions, and agreements.  If you have any questions about this policy, or the manner in which Leupold uses personal information, we encourage you to contact us.  Information on how to contact us is provided under "How to Contact Us" at the end of this policy.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Website. 

This policy applies to information we collect from or about you through this Website and in email, text and other electronic messages between you and this Website.  This policy does not apply to information collected by us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by us or any third party, including through any application or content that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website.

### Summary of Information We Collect and How We Collect It

We collect several types of information from and about visitors to our Website, including information:

  * By which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, e-mail address or telephone number (" **personal information** ").
  * That is about you but individually does not identify you, such as products and services you have ordered through our Website.
  * About your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Website and usage details.

We collect this information:

  * Directly from you when you provide it to us.
  * Automatically as you, navigate through the Website. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses and information collected through cookies and other technologies.

### Information You Provide To Us

The information we collect on or through our Website may include:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website or requesting services or support through our Website. 
  * Records and copies of your correspondence (including e-mail addresses), if you contact us, including through the “Contact Us” page of our Website,
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfillment of your orders for products, services, and support. You may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our Website.
  * Information you provide when you apply for a job through our website.

### Automatically Collected Information

As you navigate through and interact with our Website, we may automatically collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns, including:

  * Details of your visits to our Website, including traffic data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Website.
  * Information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type.

The information we collect automatically is statistical data.  It helps us to improve and administer our Website and deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to:

  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests.
  * Speed up your searches.
  * Recognize you when you return to our Website.
  * Measure what pages and features are accessed by our visitors 

We use third party services such as, Google Analytics to collect and analyze this information. The technologies we and these third party services use for this automatic data collection may include:

  * **Browser Cookies.** We may use browser cookies or similar files or scripts throughout our Website to enhance your convenience in using our Website, to improve search functionality, or to hold information that you would otherwise need to re-key. Browser cookies are text files collected by a user’s web browser. If you do not wish to accept cookies from our web site, you may configure your web browser so that it does not accept cookies; however, you may lose certain functions available on our web site.
  *  **Flash Cookies.** Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe's website. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
  *  **Web Beacons.** Pages of our the Website and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit Leupold, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity). 

We do not collect personal Information automatically, but we may tie this information to personal information about you.  For example, we link IP addresses to personally identifiable information submitted to verify whether a visitor has opted in to receiving additional information from Leupold.

You may withdraw previously provided consent, either for personal information you provided directly to us or which is automatically collected, by sending us a request through the privacy contact form which can be found in the Contact Us section of Website.

### Customer Testimonials and Product Reviews

We display on our Website testimonials, product ratings and reviews (collectively, “ **Customer Reviews** ”) posted directly to the public areas of the Website or by our customers on third party websites.  Customer Reviews, received directly from our customers, will be posted to the Website, only after having obtained your prior consent.  Consent for posting Customer Reviews from third party websites, is made in accordance with the privacy policy of the third party providing the Customer Review and this policy. 

Customer Reviews provided to us by third party services,  aggregate customer ratings and reviews from multiple third party websites, which also syndicates them.  Information on the third party service providers used by this Website can be obtained by sending us a request through the privacy contact form found in the Contact Us section of Website.

If you would like to have a customer review you have provided removed from the Website, please send us a request through the privacy contact form found in the Contact Us section of Website   Please provide sufficient information to allow us to identify the Customer Reviews that you wish to have removed.  To remove your Customer Reviews, we may require evidence confirming that you are in fact the author of such Customer Reviews.  Please note that, if we delete your Customer Reviews from the Website, copies of your Customer Reviews may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Website users.

### How We Use Your Information

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

  * To present our Website and its contents to you. 
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us, and to fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it. 
  * To provide registered users, notices about your Website account. 
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection, and to take steps at your request prior to your entering into a contract with us. 
  * To notify you about changes to this policy or our Website terms of use. 
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website. 
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information. 
  * As necessary for compliance with any law, order, or other legal obligation to which we are subject. 
  * To protect the vital interests of you or any other individual. 
  * For any other purpose with your consent. 

We may use your information to send you messages about goods and services that may be of interest to you, if you have consented to receiving such messages.  If you do not want us to use your information in this way, you can send a request to unsubscribe from receiving further marketing communications through the privacy contact form located in the Contact Us section of the Website.   

### How We Share Your Information

We may disclose aggregated information about our customers and Website users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction. 

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy: 

  * To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose to them. 
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. 
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information. 
  * To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request. 
  * To enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes. 
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Leupold, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection. 
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

### How Long We Retain Your Information

Initially, the personal information captured through this website, is initially retained for a period needed to satisfy its original intended use.  Subsequent storage, considers company policy and applicable laws and regulations when determining the overall retention period. 

### Accessing and Correcting Your Information

If you are a registered user, you can review and change some of your personal information by logging into the website and visiting your account profile page.  Registered users may also send us a note using the privacy contact form located in the Contact Us section of the Website to request access to correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us.  Some of your personal information cannot be deleted by us except by also deleting your user account. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.  

### Links

The Website may contain links to other web sites not affiliated with Leupold & Stevens, Inc., including web sites of our vendors and service providers. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. By including links to other Websites, we neither endorse such sites nor guarantee that the information they contain is accurate. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site to read the privacy statements of every linked Website as the privacy policies of each may differ from ours. This privacy statement applies solely to this Website. 

### Monitoring

We are under no obligation to monitor the conduct of Website users, but we may investigate and respond to any reported potential violations.  Any actions taken in response to a potential violation will be made at Leopold’s sole discretion and in a manner consistent with this policy and applicable laws and regulations.  This may include the deletion, removal or exclusion of content posted by users of the Website. 

### Changes to Privacy Policy

In the future, we may offer new and different programs that necessitate a change in this Policy.  We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time without prior notice.  To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, any changes to the privacy policy will be posted on this page and will be effective immediately upon posting.  However, changes to the privacy policy will not apply retroactively (i.e., to information collected prior to such changes becoming effective) unless we obtain your consent to such changes. 

### Security

We are committed to preventing others from unauthorized access to the personal information you provide to us, and we maintain commercially reasonable procedures and technology designed for this purpose. This Website has reasonable technical and organizational security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those security measures. Although we cannot guarantee that our systems are completely secure all of the time, we periodically update and test the adequacy of the processes and technologies, used to protect our customer’s and other individual’s personal information 

We suggest that you install anti-virus software on your computer and routinely check for viruses, key loggers, spyware, and other programs installed on your computer without your permission. If you believe that you have received a virus from Leupold, please contact us as soon as possible so that we may take remedial measures to remove the virus. 

We do not send e-mails to customers requesting billing, login, or password information. If you receive an e-mail purporting to be from Leupold that asks you to provide personal or account information, or login and passwords, do not provide such information unless you have first verified that the web site or e-mail is from Leupold & Stevens. Such e-mails may be fraudulent and used in connection with scams known as phishing. We asks that you report any suspicious e-mails or web sites to us.

### Additional Information for Users that are in the European Union

Users have the right to request from us access to and rectification or erasure of their personal data or restriction of processing of their personal data as well as a right to data portability. 

In addition, users may object to the processing of their personal information on grounds relating to their particular situation if it is felt that the processing of this information is not in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.  Users have the right to object at any time to the processing of personal data for direct marketing purposes. 

Users may withdraw a consent entirely or partially with future effect at any given time by following the procedures described in this Privacy Policy and – where this Privacy Policy makes no mention 

Users have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority related to data protection matters.  You can use the privacy contact form found under the Contact Us section of the Website to initiate a response to questions you might have and to obtain information how you can lodge a complaint with an appropriate supervisory authority.

### How to Contact Us Regarding Your Privacy

This Website is owned and operated by Leupold & Stevens, Inc., located at 14400 NW Greenbrier Parkway Beaverton, OR 97006-5790.  If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us using the privacy contact form found under the Contact Us section of the Website.

Product| Qty| Price  
---|---|---  
Your Cart is Empty  
Sales Tax|  Calculated at checkout   
Total| $0.00  
  
+
